Finding Aid for the Dewey Lamar Nichols Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Dewey Lamar Nichols Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0544
3 linear_feet
Reverend Dewey Lamar Nichols, originally from Newport, Tennessee, moved to Nashville in 1951 and became a member of First Baptist Church, Capitol Hill. Kelly Miller Smith, Sr. was pastor at the time. Reverend Nichols served as Minister of Evangelism for many years, being a diligent supporter of outreach services to the needy, and to the incapacitated members of First Baptist. His visits to the sick and shut-in members were always highlighted by the presentations of tapes of the worship services of First Baptist. Over the years, Reverend Nichols collected many items that formed a forty-year historical chronicle of First Baptist Church, and in 1994 shared his collection with the congregation through an exhibit. Reverend Nichols formerly worked at the Southern Baptist Publishing Board, and in 1991 moved back to his family home in Newport. The collection was donated to Special Collections in 2003. The 3 linear feet collection is divided into four series: Series I contains news items and publications related to activities at First Baptist Church, Capitol Hill; Series II relates to the Ennix-Jones Center; Series Series III is related to other churches and/or religious bodies; and, Series IV contains one rolled panoramic photograph from the 1930 National Baptist Convention. The collection is organized to correspond to the church fiscal year that runs from October to September.
- Series I - First Baptist Church, Capitol Hill
  - Annual Reports, October 1, 1994 - September 30, 1995
  - Church Bulletins
    - October 1972 - September 1973
    - October 1973 - September 1974
    - October 1975 - September 1976
    - October 1976 - September 1977
    - October 1977 - September 1978
    - October 1978 - September 1979
    - October 1979 - September 1980
    - October 1980 - September 1981
    - October 1981 - September 1982
    - October 1982 - September 1983
    - October 1983 - September 1984
    - October 1984 - September 1985
    - October 1985 - September 1986
    - October 1986 - September 1987
    - October 1987 - September 1988
    - October 1988 - September 1989
    - October 1989 - September 1990
    - October 1990 - September 1991
    - October 1991 - September 1992
    - October 1992 - September 1993
    - October 1993 - September 1994
    - October 1994 - September 1995
    - October 1995 - September 1996
    - October 1996 - September 1997
  - Church Calendars
    - October 1990 - October 1991
    - October 1994 - October 1995
    - October 1995 - October 1996
  - Church Newsletters - The Torch
    - Volume 5, October 1966 - September 1967
    - Volume 8, October 1968 - September 1969
    - Volume 10, October 1970 - September 1971
    - Volume 11, October 1971 - September 1972
    - Volume 12, October 1972 - September 1973
    - Volume 13, October 1973 - September 1974
    - Volume 14, October 1974 - September 1975
    - Volume 15, October 1975 - September 1976
    - Volume 16, October 1976 - September 1977
    - Volume 17, October 1977 - September 1978
    - Volume 18, October 1978 - September 1979
    - Volume 19, October 1979 - September 1980
    - Volume 20, October 1980 - September 1981
    - Volume 21, October 1981 - September 1982
    - Volume 22, October 1982 - September 1983
    - Volume 23, October 1983 - September 1984
    - Volume 24, October 1984 - September 1985
    - Volume 25, October 1985 - September 1986
    - Volume 26, October 1986 - September 1987
    - Volume 27, October 1987 - September 1988
    - Volume 28, October 1988 - September 1989
    - Volume 29, October 1989 - September 1990
    - Volume 30, October 1990 - September 1991
    - Volume 31, October 1991 - September 1992
    - Volume 32, October 1992 - September 1993
    - Volume 33, October 1993 - September 1994
    - Volume 34, October 1994 - September 1995
    - Volume 35, October 1995 - September 1996
    - Volume 36, October 1996 - September 1997
  - Committees
    - Program Adoption, October 1995 - September 1996
    - Debt Liquidation Committee
  - Delegates Report, American Baptist Churches of the South- Area Six, October 14-15, 1994
  - Programs
    - Anniversary
      - 112th year - December 3, 1977
      - 125th year - December 2, 1990
      - 126th year - December 1, 1991
      - 129th year - December 4, 1994
      - 130th year - December 10, 1995
    - Children's Day
      - June 11, 1995
      - June 9, 1996
    - Coretta Scott King, April 30, 1959
    - Holy Week Services
      - April 6, 1982
      - April 1, 1985
      - March 25, 1986
      - March 31, 1994
    - Installation Service - Sherman Roosevelt Tribble, January 17, 1993
    - Loyalty Day/Dinner
      - October 3, 1982
      - October 6, 1984
      - October 6, 1985
      - October 5, 1986
      - October 4, 1987
      - October 1, 1989
      - October 1, 1995
    - Maundy Thursday
      - March 23, 1978
      - April 4, 1985
      - March 31, 1994
      - April 13, 1995
    - Men's Day
      - February 22, 1976
      - February 24, 1980
      - November 6, 1988
      - July 23, 1989
      - February 18, 1990
      - February 17, 1991
      - February 21, 1993
      - February 19, 1995
    - Mother's Day, May 12, 1996
    - Pastor's Third Anniversary - Sherman Roosevelt Tribble, October 15, 1995
    - Spiritual Renewal Week
      - October 8-12, 1979
      - October 7-11, 1985
      - October 2-6, 1989
      - October 1-5, 1990
      - October 7-11, 1991
      - October 5-7, 1992
      - October 3-5, 1994
      - October 2, 1995
    - Women in Ministry, July 14, 1996
    - Women's Day
      - November 17, 1985
      - November 20, 1994
      - November 19, 1995
    - Young Adult Sunday
      - April 29, 1990
      - April 30, 1995
      - April 21, 1996
    - Youth Day
      - October 9, 1977
      - October 8, 1995
      - May 12, 1996
  - Responsive Scripture Readings, October 1994 - September 1995
  - Responsive Scripture Readings, October 1995 - September 1996
- Series II - Ennix-Jones Center
  - Flyer - Arts Bazaar, October 12, 1996
  - Newsletter - Vision to Victory, Fall 1994
  - Program - Sisters' Grace Chamber Trio, December 10, 1995
- Series III - Other Churches and/or Religious Organizations
  - Other Churches - Bulletins/Programs
    - Alpha United Baptist Church- Nashville, TN
    - Bethel Baptist Church- Morristown, TN
    - Bewley's Chapel- Russellville, TN
    - Clark Memorial United Methodist Church- Nashville, TN
    - Faith Temple Church of God in Christ- Morristown, TN
    - Fifteenth Avenue Baptist Church- Nashville, TN
    - First Baptist South Inglewood Church
    - First Street Missionary Baptist Church- Nashville, TN
    - First Unity Cathedral- Chicago, IL, n.d.
    - Greater Saint Luke Spiritual Temple- Nashville, TN
    - Lake Providence Missionary Baptist Church- Nashville, TN
    - Macedonia Baptist Church- Knoxville, TN
    - Martha Davis Baptist Church- Jefferson City, TN
    - Mount Olive Baptist Church- Morristown, TN
    - Mt. Zion Baptist Church- Nashville, TN
    - New Revelation Church of God in Christ- Nashville, TN, n.d.
    - New Zion A.M.E. Zion Church- Newport, TN
    - Rock of Ages Missionary Baptist Church- Morristown, TN, n.d., 1991, 1992
    - Rogers Memorial Baptist Church- Knoxville, TN
    - Tabernacle Baptist Church- Nashville, TN
    - Universal United House of Prayer
    - Young's Temple A.M.E.Z. Church- Hamblen County
  - Other Religious Organizations - Bulletins/Programs
    - Baptist Sunday School Board, 1989, 1995
    - Bethel District Baptist Missionary and Educational Association 96th Annual Session, July 31, 1991 - August 2, 1991
    - Interdenominational Ministers' Fellowship, May 29, 1989
    - Interdenominational Ministers' Fellowship, January 1, 1996
    - National Baptist Convention, Dedication Program
    - Other Religious Organizations- Correspondence Baptist Sunday School Board
    - Other Religious Organizations- Newsletters- The Reaper
    - Other Religious Organizations- Newsletters- The American Baptist College of ABT Seminary
      - August 1980
      - January 1985
      - April-May 1985
      - August-September 1985
    - Other Religious Organizations - Pendant National Baptist Convention, September 6-11, 1955
- Series IV - Photographs
  - National Baptist Convention - Panoramic - (1)